# **David Trail**

CONTACT 11/6 Watson Crescent  $Mobile: +44\ 7816\ 630\ 167$  INFORMATION Edinburgh Email: mr.dj.trail@gmail.com EH11 1HB DoB: 8th of January 1990

Personal Profile I am one of those people that's always been obsessed with technology, I took my degree in Computer Science not solely because it held good future prospects but because I enjoyed coding and computers, maths and physics. I have continued this love of what I do throughout my life, I have found my interests these days line up with Linux system administration, networking, security and Python.

I know that my continued interest in these will lead to my becoming an expert in that area.

**EDUCATION** 

Computer Science BSc, Heriot-Watt University September 2007 to May 2011

$2^{\rm nd}$ year	$3^{\rm rd}$ year $4^{\rm th}$ year	
Database Management	Artificial Intelligence Distributed Syste	
Discreet Mathematics	Operating Systems Parallel Technologies	
Internet Communications	Computer Graphics	Data Mining
Software Design	Professional Development	Machine Learning
Formal Specifications	Concurrency	Biological computation

#### Career

## Freelancer, Edinburgh

# Freelance work & personal projects

September 2014 onwards

- Freelance work for various clients all over the world. Generally related to Linux sysadmin or small coding jobs. Examples: Setting up OpenVPN, PPTP and L2TP/IPSec. Migrating a website from Heroku to their own VPS. DNS issues and email troubleshooting.
- Learning new Linux/BSD tools every day (Puppet, Chef) in order to better my chances of getting a job in Linux system administration or DevOps.
- Keeping my mind busy with "challenge websites" such as Project Euler and Smash the Stack

### Escuela de Idiomas, Salamanca, Spain

### Learning Spanish & code projects

July 2013 to September 2014 (1 year 2 months)

• Learned Spanish to level Intermediate 1 (B1)

- Worked on code with a group of 3 others, PostgreSQL and Django were the primary technologies involved
- Did some code every day, some of which is viewable on my Github
- I was running Arch Linux locally and ran a dedicated server which was leased out to various clients. I set up the VMs with KVM/Qemu, managed the networking and many of the clients' services

## Scotweb, Edinburgh

### Software Engineer

June 2011 to July 2013 (2 years 1 month)

- Perl, C++ and Python with Twisted Python
- Extensive use of Javascript with jQuery
- System administration of various Linux/Mac machines
- Latest web technologies (HTML5, CSS, nginx, caching, load balancing)
- General technical support

#### FEEDBACK

- "Committed and energetic. Receives feedbacks well. This task was above what we both expected. He did, however, go above and beyond to ensure my satisfaction." Mr. Marcel Wah
- "Excellent! Fast and professional work done by this guy, he located the errors instantly, and helped me all the way through to fixing it."
  Mr. Daniel Medveczky
- "Knowledgeable and friendly." and "Thanks for your passion on it by the way" Mr. BucketTse (wishes to remain anonymous)
- Many more ...

_					
$^{\rm R}$	EF	$\mathbf{E}\mathbf{B}$	E	VC	ES

Name	Dr. Greg Michaelson	Mr. Stewart Robertson
Relation	Final year supervisor	Personnel manager
Email	G.Michaelson@hw.ac.uk	stewart@scotweb.co.uk
Phone	$+44\ 131\ 451\ 3422$	+44 131 452 8357